www.linkedin.com/in/ishandahal www.github.com/ishan72 www.ishan72.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Highly analytical and technically proficient software developer with 3+ years of industry experience. Competent in full-stack software development with a proven track record as an accomplished front-end web developer. Seeking software development role anywhere in the USA.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages	JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Python, C++, Java
Front-end / Markup Languages	HTML5, CSS, Redux, SCSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Android Studio
Web Technologies	REST, Webpack
SPA Frameworks	React, Angular
Back-end Development	Node, Express
Database	PostgreSQL, MongoDB
Platforms / Cloud Service	Windows, Linux / Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
Version Controls & Tools	Git, VSCode, Github, Jira, Docker Hub, Jenkins

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SeeLogic 09/2021 - 07/2022

Software Engineer

SeeLogic is part of the DogmaGroup, focusing on CRM, ERP, and application development.

- Led the design and development of e-commerce application for Murray Uniform group, driving 200% increase in daily user count utilizing state-of-art front-end tools and technologies.
- Implemented map component consisting of complex geocoding, routing, and tracking features for integrating map-based location and tracking features in application.
- Conducted thorough unit, integration, and moretests with Jestand delivered quality and bug-free applications.
- Utilized React JS package, react-three-fiber to implement 3D graphics and visualization for intuitive product visualization.
- Managed and orchestrated the Git version control workflow for the project, overseeing branches, pull requests, and merges to ensure a streamlined and collaborative development process.
 - Environment: React JS, Tailwind CSS, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Azure DevOps, REST, Leaflet JS, Jest

InfoDevelopers Pvt. Ltd.

10/2019 - 08/2021

Software Developer

InfoDevelopers are the leading software development company targeting fin-tech and GovTech. Contributed to three GovTech projects <u>PPSC</u>, VRTMS, and <u>ORMS</u> web applications.

- Engineered robust & privilege routing and navigation within the application and achieved SPA architecture.
- Implemented role-based access control with token authentication for fortified security and precise user authorization in the applications.
- Engineered intuitive multi-level forms with validations utilizing Yup and React Forms for web app profiles.

- Used HTML Canvas and JavaScript to achieve secured media upload, manipulation and validation.
- Worked on 500+ REST APIs, including external payment gateway APIs, implementing REST architecture.
- Employed cutting-edge performance optimization techniques, incorporating lazy loading, PWA, and async loading, significantly enhancing initial page load times across a project comprising 20+ modules.

Environment: React JS, HTML Canvas, Axios, SCSS, Redux, TypeScript, Git, Jenkins, JSON, Jest

Treeleaf Technologies

06/2019 - 09/2019

Front-end Intern

Treeleaf Technologies is a leading software development company focusing on AI-powered software.

- Utilized Jest to conduct comprehensive testing, ensuring robust functionality and bug-free performance.
- Enhanced existing projects by incorporating interactive elements, such as spinners and loaders, to improve user experience and responsiveness. Developed an interactive web page for an in-house product.
- Crafted visually captivating UI/UX designs, engaging brochures, and eye-catching flyers for product launches and company promotions.

Environment: React, HTML5, CSS3, Figma, Adobe XD, Jest.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Video Analytics Solution: Developed Video Analytical Solution leveraging various GCP services such as BigQuery, Video Intelligence API, Pub/Sub and more to generate text information from videos.

IMDB Query Optimization: Worked extensively on query optimization techniques like query rewriting, join optimization, indexing and more to achieve 12% improvement in query execution time.

ER-Streamline: Used the state-of-art technologies, React, Node, MongoDB, to develop web applications to facilitate emergency services in the hospital.

Android Application - Staff Schedule Organizer: Worked with Android Studio Development to build an android application to facilitate the logging and scheduling of the office's human resources.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan-Dearborn

Dearborn, MI 48128

Master's Degree, Computer and Information Science

2024

Tribhuvan University

Kathmandu, Nepal

Bachelors in Science, Computer Science & Information Technology

2019